IU Oral History Archive 1991-1998
Indiana University Libraries
- Wilson, Douglas M. November 9, 1993, 91-214; 17 pages; 1 tape, 1 7/8 ips, 45 minutes; index, 1 VHS; Freedman, Jean
  Born in 1941, Douglas Wilson came to Indiana University in 1988 and soon became the vice president for university relations and external affairs. In this interview, he discusses the duties this position entails, including dealing with the media and the public relations of the university. Wilson speaks of certain events and phenomena he has dealt with, such as the Eigenmann shootings, the teaching versus research debate, and budget cuts and financial problems. Specifically, he cites a story involving Coach Bob Knight, the incendiary media coverage, and necessary public relations.
  Knight, Bob
  Eigenmann Hall shootings; public relations; teaching vs. research debate; university funding
- Wolfe, James July 15, 1994, 91-279; 20 pages; 1 tape, 47 minutes; index; Freedman, Jean
  Born on August 7, 1955, James Wolfe is an Indiana University alumni from the class of 1977 who went on to earn his law degree from the Indiana University School of Law in 1981. In addition, he was involved in campus politics, becoming a student trustee from 1977 through 1979. In this interview, Wolfe discusses university organization, the Indiana University School of Business, and the Indiana University School of Law. He speaks of the differences between various university presidential administrations, including that of John Ryan. Wolfe describes some of his major influences, especially Claus Clüver and Bill Haeberle, and his years working for J. Danforth Quayle.
  Indiana University School of Business; Indiana University School of Law
  Clüver, Claus; Haeberle, Bill; Ryan, John W.
  campus politics; student trusteeship; university organization
- Wolfson, Lester June 19, 1991, 91-071; 27 pages; 2 tapes, 1 7/8 ips, 89 minutes; index, 1 VHS; Freedman, Jean
  Born on September 13, 1923 Lester Wolfson is Chancellor Emeritus, and Professor Emeritus of English at Indiana University, South Bend. He rececived his A.B. from the University of Michigan in 1945, his A.M. in 1946, and his Ph.D. in 1954. In his interview he discusses the development of the regional campus system, his career at South Bend, his philosophy of education, changes in the IU campuses, and his personal career.
  Indiana University; University of Michiga; Wayne State
  Bowman, Slyvia; Buhner, Jack; Cohen, Dan; Daghlian, Phil; Gros Louis, Ken; Harrell, Charlie; Higgins, Smith; Pinnell, George; Reiberg, Rufus; Ryan, John; Stahr, Elvis; Wells, Herman B; Work, Jim
  academic counsellor; division of university extension; higher education; regional campuses; World War II
- Wong, Desmond C. January 27, 1994, 91-234; 19 pages; 2 tapes, 67 minutes; index, 1 VHS; Freedman, Jean
  Born in 1950, Desmond C. Wong is a 1973 Indiana University alumnus who earned his CPA and later went on to earn his MBA from Harvard University in 1977. Wong discusses his successful business career and his continuing involvement at Indiana University, including active participation in the Indiana University alumni association, the School of Business alumni association, and the Indiana University Foundation. In addition, he speaks of his work on the national level with the Grace Commission. Wong also discusses the issue of funding at Indiana University and the importance of university athletics, especially for alumni. He speaks of John Rau, the dean of the School of Business, and the contributions he made to that school.
  Grace Commission; Indiana University Alumni Association; Indiana University Foundation
  Rau, John
  Indiana University athletics; university funding
- Zartman, Paul A., Jr. January 31, 1993; April 8, 1993, 91-134; 22 pages; 1 cassette, 1 7/8 ips, 64 minutes; index
  Restricted: "only transcript may be quoted"
  Paul A. Zartman was born in Indianapolis in 1931. He was the son of an air force pilot during the World War II era and went to 12 different grade schools and 3 different high schools, including Shortridge High School in Indianapolis. He attended Indiana University from 1949 to 1953. In 1993, he gave two speeches at the Indiana University campus: one to OUT, a campus organization for gays and lesbians, and another to Lambda Chi Alpha fraternity, of which he was a member during his student days.
  Army ROTC; Lambda Chi Alpha; Shortridge High School; United States Air Force; Women's Air Force
  Germany
  fraternity hazing; fraternity life; homosexuality; Maginot Line; military service